

#### DEVOPS CONSULTANT

3217 Caterina Ln, College Station, Texas, 77845

□ (979) 587-5374 | Signature | Signature

## Summary\_

As a DevOps Engineer, I specialize in designing and implementing tooling to support application lifecyles. My background in systems engineering and operations enables me to efficiently work within real world constrainsts to deliver workflows and tools for building and delivering applications. I have spent several years on a software engineering team to broaden my understanding of how the application fits in the overall system. I am passionate about OSS and enjoy giving back to the OSS Community.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Senior Consultant College Station, Texas

RED HAT Mar 2021 - PRESENT

- Designed solutions to issues blocking customer migrations to Openshift 4
- Developed CI/CD pipelines along side customer engineers to accelerate value delivery
- Facilitated discovery workshops to evaluate customer needs
- Taught customer engineers new technologies and processes
- Developed operator to meet customers specific needs
- Modernized customer applications and practices to decrease technical debt
- Delivered internal conference talk to teach solutions and lessons learned to other associates

IT Systems Lead College Station, Texas

Viasat, Inc Dec 2011 - Mar 2021

- Facilitated engineer development through oversight and mentorship
- · Responsible for design and execution of operations projects, including tasking of 6 person team
- Developed customer service chatbot as part of devops team responsible for ML/AI, fulfillment, and deployment pipeline
- Managed the migration of onprem systems to both public and private cloud
- Designed data flow for Elasicsearch cluster with 120 GB daily ingest
- Maintain 15 second reads from Elasticsearch cluster with 20 TB of data
- Managed upgrade of 5 TB MySQL DB through 4 intermediate versions
- Replaced process from manual setup of servers with puppet configured servers
- Managed growth of network and systems from 5 mpbs peak to 200 mbps
- Implement storage solutions with sub millisecond latency for critical DB
- Designed PCI compliant isolated payment process to limit scope and attack surface
- Implemented network and system isolation to protect customer data
- Implemented process isolation to ensure system availablility

### **Senior IT Associate, Networking and Information Security**

Texas A&M University

• System Administrator for Network Team

- Designed and Deployed monitoring system for campus network to provide trending and status on 10,000 switchports
- · Maintain campus wide DNS and DHCP services
- · Maintain radius and nat systems for campus wireless
- · Audit security of campus VoIP systems

# **Certifications**

Jan 2022Red Hat Certified Systems AdministratorCert ID: 150-162-055Jan 2021MikroTik Certified Network AssociateCert ID: 2101NA8562Jan 2021MikroTik Certified Routing EngineerCert ID: 2101RE8620

College Station, Texas

Jan 2010 - Dec 2011

March 6, 2023 Jason Ross · Résumé

## Skills

**Languages** Python, Go, Perl, Bash, Java

**Software** Tekton, Jenkins, ArgoCD, Prometheus, Grafana, Ansible, Elasticsearch, MySQL, MariaDB, Redis

**Systems** Openshift, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP

## **Education**

Texas A&M University

B.S. IN UNIVERSITY STUDIES

College Station, Texas

Dec 2009

• Concentration: Telecommunicaitons Technology

• Minor: Communication

• Minor: Music